Kangkook Jee

Computer Science Dept., University of Texas at Dallas 800 West Campbell Road, EC-31 Richardson, TX 75080

Research Interests __

My research areas spans the general system and network security areas on the basis of operating system, compiler, binary analysis techniques. I am also interested in and have experiences in security research on different domains that include automotive, and Internet of Thing (IoT), critical infrastructure with ICS and SCADA systems.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science

New York, USA

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY 2016

• Ph.D. Thesis: "On Efficiency and Accuracy of Data Flow Tracking Systems"

• Academic Advisor: Angelos D. Keromytis

M.Phil. in Computer Science

New York, USA

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY 2012

M.Sc. in Computer Science New York, USA

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY 2007

B.S. in Mathematics & Computer ScienceSeoul, South Korea

Korea University Mar 2000

Work Expierence

University of Texas, at Dallas Richardson, TX

Assistant professor, Computer Science Department

Aug 2019 - Present

NEC Laboratories America Princeton, NJ

RESEARCHER, COMPUTER SECURITY DEPARTMENT

Sep 2014 - Jul 2019

IBM Korea Seoul, South Korea

ADVANCED TECHNICAL SUPPORT STAFF Mar. 2001 - Aug. 2006

18 Medical Company, 8th U.S. Army Seoul, South Korea

Information management staff

Jan 1997 - Mar 1999

Publications

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- C1 S. Sivakorn , **K. Jee**, Y. Sun, L. Kort-Parn, Z. Li, C. Lumezanu, Z. Wu, L. Tang, D. Li "Countering Malicious Processes with Endpoint DNS Monitoring". In Proceedings of The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), San Diego, CA, February 2019
- C2 W. U. Hassan, S. Guo, D. Li, Z. Chen, **K. Jee**, Z. Li, A. Bates "NoDoze: Combatting Threat Alert Fatigue with Automated Provenance Triage". In Proceedings of The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), San Diego, CA, February 2019

- C3 Y. Tang, D. Li, Z. Li, M. Zhang, **K. Jee**, Z. Wu, J. Rhee, X. Xiao, F. Xu, Q. Li "NodeMerge: Template Based Efficient Data Reduction For Big-Data Causality Analysis". In Proceedings of the 25th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), Toronto, Canada, November 2018.
- C4 P. Gao, X. Xiao, D. Li, Z. Li, **K. Jee**, Z. Wu, C. Kim, S. R. Kulkarni, P. Mittal "SAQL: A Stream-based Query System for Real-Time Abnormal System Behavior Detection". in Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium, August 2018, Baltimore, MD, August 2018.
- C5 P. Gao, X. Xiao, Z. Li, **K. Jee**, F. Xu, S. R. Kulkarni, P. Mittal *"AlQL: Enabling Efficient Attack Investigation from System Monitoring Data"*. In Proceedings of Usenix Annual Technical Conference (ATC), Boston, MA, June 2018.
- C6 Y. Liu, M. Zhang, D. Li, **K. Jee**, Z. Li, Z. Wu, J. Rhee, P. Mittal "Towards a Timely Causality Analysis for Enterprise Security" In Proceedings of The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), San Diego, CA, February 2018
- C7 Z. Xu, Z. Wu, Z. Li, **K. Jee**, J. Rhee, X. Xiao, F. Xu, H. Wang, G. Jiang "High fidelity data reduction for big data security dependency analyses" In Proceedings of the 23rd ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), Vienna, Austria, November 2016.
- C8 M. Pomonis, T. Petsios, **K. Jee**, M. Polychronakis, A. D. Keromytis "IntFlow: improving the accuracy of arithmetic error detection using information flow tracking" In Proceedings of Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC), New Orleans, LA. December 2014.
- C9 **K. Jee**, V. P. Kemerlis, A. D. Keromytis and G. Portokalidis "ShadowReplica: Efficient Parallelization of Dynamic Data Flow Tracking" In Proceedings of the 20th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), Berlin, Germany, November 2018.
- C10 V. P. Kemerlis, G. Portokalidis, **K. Jee**, and A. D. Keromytis "*libdft: Practical Dynamic Data Flow Tracking for Commodity System*" In Proceedings of 8th Annual International Conference on Virtual Execution Environments (VEE), London, UK, March 2012.
- C11 **K. Jee**, G. Portokalidis, V. P. Kemerlis, S. Ghosh, D. I. August, and A. D. Keromytis "A General Approach for Efficiently Accelerating Software-based Dynamic Data Flow Tracking on Commodity Hardware" In Proceedings of The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), San Diego, CA, February 2012
- C12 **K. Jee**, S. Sidiroglou-Douskos, A. Stavrou, and A. D. Keromytis. "An Adversarial Evaluation of Network Signaling and Control Mechanisms" In Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Information Security and Cryptology (ICISC), Seoul, South Korea, December 2010.

DEMOS

D1 P. Gao, X. Xiao, Z. Li, **K. Jee**, F. Xu, S. R. Kulkarni, P. Mittal "A Query System for Efficiently Investigating Complex Attack Behaviors for Enterprise Security". In Proceedings of International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB), Los Angelos, CA, August 2019.

Books

B1 K. Hayashi, **K. Jee**, O. Lascu, H. Pienaar, S. Schreitmueller, T. Tarquinio, J. Thompson "AIX 5L Practical performance and tuning guide" published by IBM Press books, ISBN-0738491799, March 2005

Patents_

APPROVED PATENTS

- P1 Host behavior and network analytics based automotive secure gateway J Rhee, H Li, Hao Shuai, CH Kim, Z Wu, LI Zhichun, **K Jee**, L Korts-Parn US Patent App. 16/146,166
- P2 Inter-application dependency analysis for improving computer system threat detection D Li, **K Jee**, Z Chen, LA Tang, LI Zhichun US Patent App. 16/006,164
- P3 Path-based program lineage inference analysis J Rhee, Z Wu, L Korts-Parn, **K Jee**, LI Zhichun, O Setayeshfar US Patent App. 16/039,993
- P4 Automated software safeness categorization with installation lineage and hybrid information sources. J Rhee, Z Wu, L Korts-Parn, **K Jee**, LI Zhichun, O Setayeshfar US Patent App. 16/040,086

- P5 Timely causality analysis in homogeneous enterprise hosts. M Zhang, K Jee, Z Li, D Li, Z Wu, J Rhee, US Patent 15/972,911, issued on Nov 2018.
- P6 Template based data reduction for security related information flow. data. D Li, K Jee, Z Wu, M Zhang, Z Li. US Patent 15/979,512, issued on Nov 2018.
- P7 Template based data reduction for commercial data mining. D Li, K Jee, Z Wu, M Zhang, Z Li. US Patent 15/979,514, issued on Nov 2018.
- P8 Blackbox Program Privilege Flow Analysis with Inferred Program Behavior Context. J Rhee, Y Jeon, Z LI, K Jee, Z Wu, G Jiang. US Patent 15/623,538, issued on Feb 2018.
- P9 Fine-Grained Analysis and Prevention of Invalid Privilege Transitions. J Rhee, Y Jeon, Z LI, K Jee, Z Wu, G Jiang. US Patent 15/623,589, issued on Feb 2018.
- P10 Automated blackbox inference of external origin user behavior. Z Wu, J Rhee, Y Jeon, Z Li, K Jee, G Jiang. US Patent 15/652,796, issued on Feb 2018.
- P11 Host level detect mechanism for malicious dns activities. **K Jee**, Z LI, G Jiang, L Korts-Parn, Z Wu, Y Sun, J Rhee. US Patent 15/644,018, issued on Jan 2018.
- P12 Extraction and comparison of hybrid program binary features. J Rhee, Z Li, Z Wu, K Jee, G Jiang. US Patent 15/479,928, issued on Oct 2017.
- P13 High Fidelity Data Reduction for System Dependency Analysis. Z Wu, Z Li, J Rhee, F Xu, G Jiang, K Jee, X Xiao, Z Xu. US Patent 15/416,346 issued on Aug 2017
- P14 Intrusion Detection Using Efficient System Dependency Analysis. Z Wu, Z Li, J Rhee, F Xu, G Jiang, K Jee, X Xiao, Z Xu, J Rhee. US Patent 15/416,462, issued on Aug 2017

Teaching

Introduction to Programming (COMSW3101-003)

New York, USA

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

Fall 2013

Designed and taught a course, Programming with Python (Students: 14, Course evaluations: 4.45 / 5.0)

Teaching Assistant New York, USA

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

2010-2012

- Spring 2012: Teaching Assistant (TA) for Artificial Intelligence (COMSW4701)
- Fall 2010: Teaching Assistant (TA) for Introduction to Programming (COMS3157)

Student Advising_

Intern Advising

NEC LABS AMERICA

- Summer 2015: Yasser Shalabi (Ph.D candidate at UIUC).
 - Project: Fast and efficient system event collection from Linux kernel.
- Summer 2016: Yixin Sun (Ph.D candidate at Princeton University). Project: Analyzing Program DNS Behavior under Malware Injection.
- Summer 2017: Suphanee Sivakorn (Ph.D candidate at Columbia University).
 - Project: System to Detect Malicious Processes with End-point DNS Monitoring.
- Summer 2018: Oi Wang (Ph.D candidate at UIUC).
 - Project: End-point Detection and Response for IoT Devices.
- Summer 2019: Qi Wang (Ph.D candidate at UIUC).
 - Project: SplitBrain: Edge-Cloud Collaborative Security for IoT.

Student Mentoring

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

- Fall 2012: Mengqi Zhang (MS student Columbia University, currently software engineer at Facebook)
 Project: Compiler (LLVM) assisted program instrumentation and hardening
- Spring 2013: Daniel Song (MS student at Columbia University, currently Ph.D candidate at Rice University)
 Project: Comparison study of Dynamic Binary Instrumentation (DBI) frameworks
- Fall 2013: Marios Pomonis, Theofilos Petsios (Ph.D candidates at Columbia University)

 Project: Arithmetic error detection using information flow tracking with compiler assisted program instrumentation.

Talks

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

NDSS, Sand Diego, USA	"Countering Malicious Processes with Process-DNS Association"	Feb 2019
ACM CCS, Toronto, Canada	"NodeMerge: Template Based Efficient Data Reduction For Big-Data Causality Analysis"	Nov 2018
ACM CCS, Berlin, Germany	"ShadowReplica: Efficient Parallelization of Dynamic Data Flow Tracking"	Nov 2013
NDSS, San Diego, USA	"A General Approach for Efficiently Accelerating Software-based Dynamic Data Flow Tracking on Commodity Hardware"	Feb 2012
ICISC, Seoul, South Korea	"An Adversarial Evaluation of Network Signaling and Control Mechanisms"	Dec 2010

INVITED TALKS

Apr 2019	"Finding Flow: Connecting the Dots to Disclose Attacker Trails"	NSR (National Security Research Institute), Daejon, South Korea
Apr 2019	"Finding Flow: Connecting the Dots to Disclose Attacker Trails"	KAIST, Daejon, South Korea
Apr 2019	"Finding Flow: Connecting the Dots to Disclose Attacker Trails"	SKKU, Suwon, South Korea
Dec 2018	"Research Challenges and Opportunities in End-point Detection and Response (EDR)"	Security & Privacy PIC Seminar Series, IBM Watson Research
Oct 2013	"ShadowReplica: Efficient Parallelization of Dynamic Data Flow Tracking"	Security Group Seminar, Stevens Institute of Technology
Jun 2012	"A General Approach for Efficiently Accelerating Software-based Dynamic Data Flow Tracking on Commodity Hardware"	IBM PL Day, IBM T. J. Watson Research Center
Mar 2011	"A General Approach for Efficiently Accelerating Software-based Dynamic Data Flow Tracking on Commodity Hardware"	Liberty Group Seminar, Princeton University

Honors & Awards

2016	CEATEC Award, Innovation for better society, CEATEC Japan CPS/IoT Exhibition	Tokyo, Japan
2014	2nd Place CyberSecurity for the Next Generation 2014: Americas Round, Kaspersky lab	Washington, DC
2008-201	4 Graduate Fellowship , Graduate Research Assistantship (GRA), Columbia University	New York, USA
2003-200	5 IBM top-talented group (resource pool for future executives), IBM Korea	Seoul, South Korea
2005	Employee education program with full tuition support, IBM Korea	Seoul, South Korea
2004	IBM Stock option (500 stocks), IBM Korea	Seoul, South Korea
2000	Army Commendation Medal, 8th U.S. Army	Seoul, South Korea

Service____

TECHNICAL PROGRAM COMMITTEE MEMBER

ISC 2016 International Conference on Information Security Conference

EXTERNAL REVIEWER

CCS ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security: 2012, 2013, 2014

NDSS International Workshop on Security: 2015

INFOCOM IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications: 2015

RAID International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions and Defenses: 2014, 2015

ACNS Applied Cryptography and Network Security: 2015

CANS USENIX Workshop on Cyber Security Experimentation and Test: 2011
International Conference on Cryptology And Network Security: 2011
International Conference on Information Security Conference: 2011

IWSEC International Workshop on Security: 2013

Research Experience

Researcher, NEC Laboratories America, Sep 2014 - Present.

Protection of Machine Learning Algorithm with Hardware Assistance (Mar 2018 - Present): To protect the privacy of ML algorithms, I co-designed the ML platform that runs the algorithm inside Intel SGX and encrypts the channel for GPU communication.

Application White-listing with Binary Triage (Mar 2018 - Present): I proposed and work on a white-listing solution that dynamically updates the reputation of application binary considering new metrics related to the trustworthiness of the binary.

End-point Detection and Response for IoT devices (Sep 2017 - Present): In this project, we develop an EDR solution for IoT devices. To minimize the interference to the operation of IoT device, our approach only remains minimal workload to IoT devices and offload the rest to the cloud to protect IoT deployment with ML-based anomaly detection and support for forensic analysis.

Enterprise security solution for ML detection and forensic support (Sep 2014 - Aug 2017): Autonomous Security intelligence (ASI) is an award-winning security solution that monitors and collects system activities from a large number of end-hosts to support ML-based anomaly detection and forensic analysis. I designed and developed auditing components for different end-hosts (Linux, OS X, IoT platforms). I was mainly in charge of the threat intelligence and the analysis the latest attack trend.

Research Assistant, Columbia University, Sep 2008 - Aug 2014.

IntFlow (Jun 2012 - Jul 2012): IntFlow is a compiler extension which uses static data-flow analysis to report integer errors, taking into account common developer practices to reduce false positives. IntFlow achieves 89% reduction in false positives compared to the Clang-based Integer Overflow Checker (IOC).

ShadowReplica, (Jan 2012 - June 2013): ShadowReplica accelerates DFT and other shadow memory-based analyses, by decoupling analysis from execution and utilizing spare CPU cores to run them in parallel. DFT is run in parallel by a shadow thread that is spawned for each application thread, and the two communicate using a shared data structure. We avoid the problems suffered by previous approaches, by introducing an offline application analysis phase that utilizes both static and dynamic analysis approaches to generate optimized code for decoupling execution and implementing DFT, while it also minimizes the amount of information needed for communication between two threads.

Taint Flow Algebra (TFA), (Jan 2010 - Dec 2011): To improve the efficiency of DFT, our approach separates the program logic from the corresponding tracking logic, extracting the semantics of the latter and ab-

stracting them using an intermediate representation(IR) of Taint Flow Algebra. We then apply optimization techniques to eliminate redundant tracking logic and minimize interference with the target program.

libdft, (Jan 2010 - Dec 2011): Dynamic data flow tracking (DFT) deals with tagging and tracking data of interest as they propagate during program execution. We presented libdft, a dynamic DFT framework that unlike previous work is at once fast, reusable, and works with commodity software and hardware. libdft provides an API for building DFT-enabled tools that work on unmodified binaries, running on common operating systems and hardware, thus facilitating research and rapid prototyping.

Evaluation of control plane mechanisms in propagating security updates, (June 2008 - July 2010) The project measured and evaluated the reliability and performance trade-offs for a variety of control channel mechanisms that are suitable for coordinating large-scale collaborative defenses when under attack. Our results show that the performance and reliability characteristics change drastically when one evaluates the systems under attack by a sophisticated and targeted adversary.